## Adrian Gutierrez Diaz

Villa Clara, Cuba

agd.vcl@gmail.com; dagiaz.16mb.com Phone number: +53 53 610 831

## Summary

Software developer with more than 10 years of experience lately focused on backend web applications, mainly using JavaScript and PHP. Involved in the development of client-server management systems using Delphi and Visual FoxPro and several database engines. Lover of new technologies.

# Working experience

Software developer and Informatics Specialist · Tourism Sector Electronic Group (GET) Villa Clara, Cuba. Since Jun. 2015

Software technical assistance for tourism enterprises. Management of Microsoft SQL Databases. Development of web applications for enterprise contracts management.

Key tools and technologies: MS SQL Server, Transact-SQL, HTML, Javascript, PHP, Node is, JQuery, Angular. Bootstrap, AJAX, MongoDB.

#### Freelance Software and Web Developer Villa Clara, Cuba

Jun, 2015 - Nov. 2017

- Development of financial crawlers (Isofact, Spain). Main developer of FDPromociones Intranet for gifts requesting from FidelyNET Platform, http://intranet.fdpromociones.com (Isofact, Spain).

Development and Maintenance of new modules of Estudiored website for managing editor's publications, www.gestioncentral.net (Belua, Venezuela). Main developer of Envialia Shipping System (Belua, Venezuela).

Key tools and technologies: Java, Node js, Mysql, HTML, Javascript, PHP, Jquery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Angular RESTful and SOAP Webservices.

Part-time

#### Freelance Web Developer Villa Clara, Cuba

2012 – Jun. 2015

Main software developer of two educational HTML games (Mattris and Matsum) using Maths as key concept (Colombia). Development and Maintenance of new modules for the Health Admission System (desktop and web versions) (Avances Co., Colombia). Main developer of an Interactive Auto Managed Map System (Entersys, Mexico)

<u>Key tools and technologies</u>: Visual Foxpro, MS SQLServer, Mysql, HTML, Javascript, PHP, Jquery, Canvas Libreries, AJAX, Phonegap Part-time

#### Informatics Specialist · FINTUR SA villa Clara, Cuba

May. 2007 - Jun. 2015

Windows and Linux networks administrator. Software developer of applications for summarizing financial data of clients. Development of a web application for visualizing financial information in real time to clients. Member of the Financial Management System SABIC group (Windows platform)

Key tools and technologies: Delphi, Foxpro, Visual Foxpro, MS SQLServer, Mysql, HTML, Javascript, PHP, ExtJs, Jquery, AJAX

#### Computer Science Specialist · La Granjita Hotel Villa Clara, Cuba

Nov. 2005 – Apr. 2007

Windows and Unix networks administrator. Web developer, author of the Hotel Shopping Requests System. Key tools and technologies: HTML, Javascript, ASP, CSS, Foxpro

### Education

Automatic Engineering Villa Clara, Cuba

1998 - 2003

Electric Engineering Faculty – Universidad Central "Marta Abreu" de Las Villas Engineer thesis "Industrial systems supervision through web applications" Key concepts and technologies: TCP/IP, Sockets, SCADA, Labview, HTML, Javascript, Delphi

Grade: 5.0 (Summa cum Laude)